Department of Physical Education and Athletics Records UA046
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Department of Physical Education and Athletics Records
1940 -- 1989
1850 -- 2020
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Department of Physical Education
UA046
227.8 Linear Feet 201 boxes and 20 oversize folders
29 Volumes
1 Artifact(s) 6.5 inches wide by 7.5 inches long by 23.5 inches tall
31 Audiovisual Object(s)
534 Digital Object(s)
40 Web sites
This collection contains the records of the Department of Physical Education and Athletics.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list. This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by the Department of Physical Education and Athletics, 2000-2017.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into thirteen series: Team files; Subject files; Photographs, negatives, and Scientific Baseball (manual); Videos; Scrapbooks; Playbooks; Programs and publications; Constitution for Government of Athletics and meeting minutes; Ephemera; Jumbo Footprints; Athletics Department web crawls; Unprocessed accessions; and 2017 accessions.
Related Materials
Jumbo Club Records, 1969-2008. Tufts University. Digital Collections and Archives. Medford, MA.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains team files, subject files, photographs and negatives, manager's reports, scrapbooks, playbooks, programs and publications, ephemera, and materials from Jumbo Footprints dating from 1870. These records were created by the athletic department to record sporting events, committee meetings, activities of the year, special events, fundraising activities. The records include rosters, playbooks, mangers reports, and game results for various sports. Also included are summary records of the season events such as annual reports, end of season reports, awards and news releases.
Biographical / Historical
Athletics at Tufts began in the 1860s. Football was introduced in 1863, followed by baseball in 1864. Though athletic teams were organized by students until the early twentieth century, a physical education requirement was put into place in 1865, and the Department of Physical Education was created in the 1880s. The physical education requirement lasted at Tufts until 1975, when it was dropped by vote of the Trustees. During the nineteenth century, Tufts' athletics suffered from a lack of facilities. Athletics had a casual role on campus during the nineteenth century. Although the Tufts Athletic Association was founded in the fall of 1874, it oversaw only "track and field sports." During this period, most sports were organized by the students themselves, the equivalent of intramural sports today, and annual Field days served as a venue for competitions. Field sports were abandoned due to lack of interest between 1882-1892, but renewed enthusiasm during the 1890s resulted in new facilities built on campus, including the construction of a track at the Oval, and an indoor running track in Goddard Gymnasium. Throughout the early twentieth century, the Trustees had a conflicted relationship with athletics. Though athletic teams were growing in popularity across college campuses nationwide, the Trustees were wary of the growing "professionalism in athletics." Fearing the prioritization of campus athletics over Tufts' academics, the Trustees announced that financial aid could only come from alumni funding, and not from trustee funding. However, as Tufts fell behind in competitions, and as it became clear that smaller colleges such as Tufts could gain recognition through athletics, the idea of "recruiting students competent both on the athletic field and in the classroom" became much more popular. Tufts joined the Intercollegiate Athletic Association of the United States in 1906. The appointment of John Albert Cousens as the president of the university in 1919 was a key influence in the future of Tufts athletics. Cousens, Class of 1898 and a football player during his undergraduate years, was a firm believer in the necessity of athletics during the college years. Cousens also appointed Clarence "Pop" Houston as the first athletic director of Tufts. Houston emphasized the idea of recruiting good athletes to Tufts, as long as they could meet the academic standards. Cousens' appointment to the presidency was a driving force in aligning the Department of Physical Education more closely with the academic departments; during the 1920s, the physical education graduation requirement was increased, and physical education took place during regular class hours. In 1932, the Trustees named the newly-built gymnasium on College Avenue in his honor, due to his strong beliefs about personal physical fitness and due to his help while fundraising to build the new gymnasium. Athletics during the 1960s and 1970s was characterized by a changing athletic body. Title IX going into effect in 1972 brought about an increase in funding for women's athletic teams. Tufts also joined the New England Small College Athletic Conference (NESCAC) in 1971, which reflected its ongoing dedication to operating athletics "in harmony" with the school's academic standards and philosophies. NESCAC defined several restrictive rules governing Tufts athletics that defined much of its athletic culture, including rules prohibiting off-campus recruiting, limiting the number of "contests" in each sport, and having strict beginning and end dates. As of 2017, Tufts is still a member of the conference.
Curriculum and Instruction -- Academic Departments and Programs; Student Activities -- Athletics; Curriculum and Instruction -- Scholarships, Fellowships, Awards
- Team files, 1874 -- 2011; 1970 -- 1990; UA046.001; 44.9 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  Team files include rosters, game results and season summaries from 1889 to 1994. Files are arranged by sport and chronologically within each sport. While the football files are the most comprehensive, sports such as track, wrestling, basketball, and baseball are well represented in the early years. By the 1970s, other sports such as soccer, lacrosse, field hockey, softball and sailing begin to appear. Included are photocopies of memory books created by the women's lacrosse team during the period of 1983-1991 and a sampling of manager's reports for most sports that spans the period from 1925 to 1989.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically by sport.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Outdoor track, 1907 -- 1939; UA046.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
    Track and Field
  - Indoor track, 1941 -- 1946; UA046.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Indoor track, 1947 -- 1948; UA046.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Outdoor track, 1948; UA046.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Indoor track, 1952 -- 1953; UA046.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Outdoor track, 1953; UA046.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Indoor track, 1953 -- 1954; UA046.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Outdoor track, 1954; UA046.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - Indoor track, 1954 -- 1955; UA046.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - Outdoor track, 1956; UA046.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - Outdoor track, 1957; UA046.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Outdoor track, 1962; UA046.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - Indoor track, 1965 -- 1966; UA046.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
  - Indoor track, 1966 -- 1967; UA046.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - Men's outdoor track, 1967; UA046.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
  - Indoor track, 1967 -- 1968; UA046.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
  - Men's outdoor track, 1968; UA046.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
  - Indoor track, 1968 -- 1969; UA046.001.001.00018 (Box 1)
  - Men's outdoor track, 1969; UA046.001.001.00019 (Box 1)
  - Indoor track, cm, 1969 -- 1970; UA046.001.001.00020 (Box 1)
  - Men's outdoor track, 1970; UA046.001.001.00021 (Box 1)
  - Indoor track, CM, 1970 -- 1971; UA046.001.001.00022 (Box 1)
  - Outdoor track, 1971; UA046.001.001.00023 (Box 1)
  - Men's indoor track, 1971 -- 1972; UA046.001.001.00024 (Box 1)
  - Men's indoor track, 1972 -- 1973; UA046.001.001.00025 (Box 1)
  - Men's indoor track, 1973; UA046.001.001.00026 (Box 1)
  - GBL records, 1976; UA046.001.001.00027 (Box 1)
  - New England outdoor track and field championships, 1974; UA046.001.001.00028 (Box 1)
  - [Track] GBCTM winter, 1973 -- 1974; UA046.001.001.00029 (Box 1)
  - New England track, 1975; UA046.001.001.00030 (Box 1)
  - Men's indoor track, 1974 -- 1975; UA046.001.001.00031 (Box 1)
  - [Track] GBC championship, 1975; UA046.001.001.00032 (Box 1)
  - Men's indoor track, 1975 -- 1976; UA046.001.001.00033 (Box 1)
  - Track easterns, 1976; UA046.001.001.00034 (Box 1)
  - Track GBC's, 1976; UA046.001.001.00035 (Box 1)
  - Track New Englands, 1976; UA046.001.001.00036 (Box 1)
  - Men's and women's track, 1976 -- 1977; UA046.001.001.00037 (Box 1)
  - Women's outdoor track, 1977; UA046.001.001.00038 (Box 1)
  - [Track] ECAC's, 1977 (Easterns), UA046.001.001.00039 (Box 1)
  - 18th Annual Greater Boston indoor track and field championships, 1977; UA046.001.001.00040 (Box 1)
  - Men's indoor track, 1977 -- 1978; UA046.001.001.00041 (Box 1)
  - Women's track, 1977 -- 1978; UA046.001.001.00042 (Box 1)
  - Men's outdoor track, 1978; UA046.001.001.00043 (Box 1)
  - EAIW (track), 1978; UA046.001.001.00044 (Box 1)
  - Women's indoor track, 1978 -- 1979; UA046.001.001.00045 (Box 1)
  - Men's indoor track, 1978 -- 1979; UA046.001.001.00046 (Box 1)
  - Men's outdoor track, 1979; UA046.001.001.00047 (Box 1)
  - [Track] ECAC tourney, 1979; UA046.001.001.00048 (Box 1)
  - [Track] ECAC's, 1979; UA046.001.001.00049 (Box 1)
  - Men's indoor track, 1979 -- 1980; UA046.001.001.00050 (Box 1)
  - Women's indoor track, 1979 -- 1980; UA046.001.001.00051 (Box 1)
  - Men's outdoor track, 1980; UA046.001.001.00052 (Box 1)
  - Men's indoor track, 1980 -- 1981; UA046.001.001.00053 (Box 1)
  - Men's outdoor track, 1981; UA046.001.001.00054 (Box 1)
  - Women's outdoor track, 1981; UA046.001.001.00055 (Box 1)
  - Men's indoor track, 1981 -- 1982; UA046.001.001.00056 (Box 1)
  - Women's indoor track, 1981 -- 1982; UA046.001.001.00057 (Box 1)
  - Men's outdoor track, 1982; UA046.001.001.00058 (Box 1)
  - Women's track, 1982; UA046.001.001.00059 (Box 1)
  - Men's indoor track, 1982 -- 1983; UA046.001.001.00060 (Box 1)
  - Women's indoor track, 1982 -- 1983; UA046.001.001.00061 (Box 1)
  - Men's indoor track, 1982 -- 1983; UA046.001.001.00062 (Box 1)
  - Women's indoor track, 1983 -- 1984; UA046.001.001.00063 (Box 1)
  - Men's outdoor track, 1984; UA046.001.001.00064 (Box 1)
  - Women's outdoor track, 1984; UA046.001.001.00065 (Box 1)
  - Women's outdoor track, 1983; UA046.001.001.00066 (Box 1)
  - Men's indoor track, 1984 -- 1985; UA046.001.001.00067 (Box 1)
  - Women's indoor track, 1984 -- 1985; UA046.001.001.00068 (Box 1)
  - ECAC track, 1985; UA046.001.001.00069 (Box 1)
  - Men' outdoor track, 1985; UA046.001.001.00070 (Box 1)
  - Women's outdoor track, 1985; UA046.001.001.00071 (Box 1)
  - Men's indoor track, 1985 -- 1986; UA046.001.001.00072 (Box 1)
  - Women's indoor track, 1985 -- 1986; UA046.001.001.00073 (Box 1)
  - Men's outdoor track, 1986; UA046.001.001.00074 (Box 1)
  - Women's outdoor track, 1986; UA046.001.001.00075 (Box 1)
  - Men's indoor track, 1986 -- 1987; UA046.001.001.00076 (Box 1)
  - Women's indoor track, 1986 -- 1987; UA046.001.001.00077 (Box 1)
  - Women's indoor track, 1980 -- 1981; UA046.001.001.00078 (Box 1)
  - Men's outdoor track, 1987; UA046.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - Women's outdoor track, 1987; UA046.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - Women's outdoor ECAC track, 1987; UA046.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - Men's indoor ECAC track, 1987 -- 1988; UA046.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - Women's indoor track, 1987 -- 1988; UA046.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - Men's outdoor track, 1987 -- 1988; UA046.001.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - Women's outdoor track, 1987 -- 1988; UA046.001.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - Men's and women's indoor track, 1988 -- 1989; UA046.001.002.00008 (Box 2)
  - Men's and women's outdoor track, 1989; UA046.001.002.00009 (Box 2)
  - Men's indoor track, 1989; UA046.001.002.00010 (Box 2)
  - Women's indoor track, 1989 -- 1990; UA046.001.002.00011 (Box 2)
  - Hockey history, 1956 -- 1987; UA046.001.002.00012 (Box 2)
    Ice Hockey
  - Hockey lettermen, 1943 -- 1960; UA046.001.002.00013 (Box 2)
  - Hockey, 1946 -- 1947; UA046.001.002.00014 (Box 2)
  - Hockey, 1948 -- 1950; UA046.001.002.00015 (Box 2)
  - Hockey, 1950 -- 1951; UA046.001.002.00016 (Box 2)
  - Hockey, 1951 -- 1952; UA046.001.002.00017 (Box 2)
  - Hockey, 1952 -- 1953; UA046.001.002.00018 (Box 2)
  - Hockey, 1953 -- 1954; UA046.001.002.00019 (Box 2)
  - Hockey, 1954 -- 1955; UA046.001.002.00020 (Box 2)
  - Hockey, 1956 -- 1957; UA046.001.002.00021 (Box 2)
  - Hockey games, 1986 -- 1987; UA046.001.002.00022 (Box 2)
  - Hockey, 1985 -- 1987; UA046.001.002.00023 (Box 2)
  - Hockey, 1987 -- 1988; UA046.001.002.00024 (Box 2)
  - Ice hockey, 1987 -- 1988; UA046.001.002.00025 (Box 2)
  - Hockey games, 1987 -- 1988; UA046.001.002.00026 (Box 2)
  - ECAC tourney/hockey, 1988; UA046.001.002.00027 (Box 2)
  - Hockey, 1989 -- 1990; UA046.001.002.00028 (Box 2)
  - Golf, 1939; UA046.001.002.00029 (Box 2)
    Golf
  - Golf, 1948; UA046.001.002.00030 (Box 2)
  - Golf, 1953; UA046.001.002.00031 (Box 2)
  - Golf, 1953 -- 1991; UA046.001.002.00032 (Box 2)
  - Golf, 1954; UA046.001.002.00033 (Box 2)
  - Golf, 1956; UA046.001.002.00034 (Box 2)
  - Golf, 1957; UA046.001.002.00035 (Box 2)
  - Golf, 1962 -- 1963; UA046.001.002.00036 (Box 2)
  - Golf, 1967 -- 1968; UA046.001.002.00037 (Box 2)
  - Golf, 1969; UA046.001.002.00038 (Box 2)
  - Golf, 1970; UA046.001.002.00039 (Box 2)
  - Golf, 1971 -- 1972; UA046.001.002.00040 (Box 2)
  - Golf, 1974; UA046.001.002.00041 (Box 2)
  - Golf, 1976; UA046.001.002.00042 (Box 2)
  - Golf team, 1978 -- 1979; UA046.001.002.00043 (Box 2)
  - Golf, 1977; UA046.001.002.00044 (Box 2)
  - Golf, 1978; UA046.001.002.00045 (Box 2)
  - Golf team, 1978 -- 1979; UA046.001.002.00046 (Box 2)
  - Men's varsity golf, 1979; UA046.001.002.00047 (Box 2)
  - Golf, 1980; UA046.001.002.00048 (Box 2)
  - Golf, 1981; UA046.001.002.00049 (Box 2)
  - Golf, 1982; UA046.001.002.00050 (Box 2)
  - Golf, 1982 -- 1983; UA046.001.002.00051 (Box 2)
  - Golf, 1984; UA046.001.002.00052 (Box 2)
  - Golf, 1986; UA046.001.002.00053 (Box 2)
  - Golf, 1985; UA046.001.002.00054 (Box 2)
  - Golf, 1986; UA046.001.002.00055 (Box 2)
  - Golf, 1987; UA046.001.002.00056 (Box 2)
  - Golf, 1987 -- 1988; UA046.001.002.00057 (Box 2)
  - Golf, 1989; UA046.001.002.00058 (Box 2)
  - Men's soccer, 1939; UA046.001.002.00059 (Box 2)
    Soccer
  - Men's soccer, 1946; UA046.001.002.00060 (Box 2)
  - Mens' soccer, 1947; UA046.001.002.00061 (Box 2)
  - Men's soccer, 1948; UA046.001.002.00062 (Box 2)
  - Men's soccer, 1949; UA046.001.002.00063 (Box 2)
  - Men's soccer, 1950; UA046.001.002.00064 (Box 2)
  - Men's soccer, 1951; UA046.001.002.00065 (Box 2)
  - Men's soccer, 1952; UA046.001.002.00066 (Box 2)
  - Men's soccer, 1953; UA046.001.002.00067 (Box 2)
  - Men's soccer, 1954; UA046.001.002.00068 (Box 2)
  - Men's soccer, 1964; UA046.001.002.00069 (Box 2)
  - Men's soccer, 1965; UA046.001.002.00070 (Box 2)
  - Men's soccer, 1966; UA046.001.002.00071 (Box 2)
  - Men's soccer, 1967; UA046.001.002.00072 (Box 2)
  - Men's soccer, 1968; UA046.001.002.00073 (Box 2)
  - Men's soccer, 1969; UA046.001.002.00074 (Box 2)
  - Men's soccer, 1970; UA046.001.002.00075 (Box 2)
  - Men's soccer, 1971; UA046.001.002.00076 (Box 2)
  - Men's soccer, 1947 -- 1972; UA046.001.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - Men's soccer, 1973; UA046.001.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Men's soccer, 1974; UA046.001.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - Men's soccer, 1975; UA046.001.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - Men's soccer, 1976; UA046.001.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - Men's soccer, 1976; UA046.001.003.00006 (Box 3)
  - Men's soccer, 1977; UA046.001.003.00007 (Box 3)
  - Men's soccer, 1978; UA046.001.003.00008 (Box 3)
  - Men's soccer, 1979; UA046.001.003.00009 (Box 3)
  - Men's soccer, 1979; UA046.001.003.00010 (Box 3)
  - Men's soccer, 1981; UA046.001.003.00011 (Box 3)
  - Men's soccer, 1982; UA046.001.003.00012 (Box 3)
  - Men's soccer, 1983; UA046.001.003.00013 (Box 3)
  - Men's soccer, 1984; UA046.001.003.00014 (Box 3)
  - Men's soccer, 1985; UA046.001.003.00015 (Box 3)
  - Men's soccer, 1986; UA046.001.003.00016 (Box 3)
  - Women's soccer, 1979; UA046.001.003.00017 (Box 3)
  - Women's soccer, 1980; UA046.001.003.00018 (Box 3)
  - Women's soccer, 1981; UA046.001.003.00019 (Box 3)
  - Women's soccer, 1982; UA046.001.003.00020 (Box 3)
  - Women's soccer, 1983; UA046.001.003.00021 (Box 3)
  - Women's soccer, 1984; UA046.001.003.00022 (Box 3)
  - Women's soccer, 1985; UA046.001.003.00023 (Box 3)
  - Women's soccer, 1986; UA046.001.003.00024 (Box 3)
  - Women's soccer, 1987; UA046.001.003.00025 (Box 3)
  - Men's soccer, 1987 -- 1988; UA046.001.003.00026 (Box 3)
  - Men's soccer, 1988; UA046.001.003.00027 (Box 3)
  - Women's soccer, 1988; UA046.001.003.00028 (Box 3)
  - Women's soccer, 1989; UA046.001.003.00029 (Box 3)
  - Men's soccer, 1989; UA046.001.003.00030 (Box 3)
  - Women's squash, 1975 -- 1976; UA046.001.003.00031 (Box 3)
    Squash
  - Squash, 1976 -- 1977; UA046.001.003.00032 (Box 3)
  - Squash, 1978 -- 1979; UA046.001.003.00033 (Box 3)
  - Men's squash, 1978; UA046.001.003.00034 (Box 3)
  - Women's squash, 1978 -- 1979; UA046.001.003.00035 (Box 3)
  - Squash, 1979 -- 1980; UA046.001.003.00036 (Box 3)
  - Men's squash, 1980; UA046.001.003.00037 (Box 3)
  - Squash, 1981 -- 1982; UA046.001.003.00038 (Box 3)
  - Men's and women's squash, 1982 -- 1983; UA046.001.003.00039 (Box 3)
  - Squash, 1983 -- 1984; UA046.001.003.00040 (Box 3)
  - Men's squash, 1984 -- 1985; UA046.001.003.00041 (Box 3)
  - Men's squash, 1985 -- 1986; UA046.001.003.00042 (Box 3)
  - Women's squash, 1985 -- 1986; UA046.001.003.00043 (Box 3)
  - Men's and women's squash, 1990 -- 1991; UA046.001.003.00044 (Box 3)
  - Squash, 1986 -- 1987; UA046.001.003.00045 (Box 3)
  - Men's and women's squash, 1987 -- 1988; UA046.001.003.00046 (Box 3)
  - Men's and women's squash, 1988 -- 1989; UA046.001.003.00047 (Box 3)
  - Men's and women's squash, 1989 -- 1990; UA046.001.003.00048 (Box 3)
  - Squash official yearbook, 1991 -- 1992; UA046.001.003.00049 (Box 3)
  - Baseball results schedule, 1921 -- 1941; UA046.001.003.00050 (Box 3)
    Baseball
  - Baseball press releases, schedule, pictures, 1946; UA046.001.003.00052 (Box 3)
  - Baseball, 1948; UA046.001.003.00053 (Box 3)
  - Baseball, 1949; UA046.001.003.00054 (Box 3)
  - Baseball, 1950; UA046.001.003.00055 (Box 3)
  - Baseball, 1951; UA046.001.003.00056 (Box 3)
  - Baseball, 1952; UA046.001.003.00057 (Box 3)
  - Baseball, 1953; UA046.001.003.00058 (Box 3)
  - Baseball, 1954; UA046.001.003.00059 (Box 3)
  - Baseball, 1955; UA046.001.003.00060 (Box 3)
  - Baseball, 1956; UA046.001.003.00061 (Box 3)
  - Baseball, 1957; UA046.001.003.00062 (Box 3)
  - Baseball, 1957; UA046.001.004.00001 (Box 4)
  - Baseball, 1958; UA046.001.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - Baseball, 1959; UA046.001.004.00003 (Box 4)
  - Baseball GBL, 1960; UA046.001.004.00004 (Box 4)
  - Baseball GBL, 1961; UA046.001.004.00005 (Box 4)
  - GBL Baseball, 1962; UA046.001.004.00006 (Box 4)
  - GBL Baseball, 1963; UA046.001.004.00007 (Box 4)
  - Baseball, 1964; UA046.001.004.00008 (Box 4)
  - Baseball, 1965; UA046.001.004.00009 (Box 4)
  - Baseball, 1966; UA046.001.004.00010 (Box 4)
  - Tufts baseball, 1966; UA046.001.004.00011 (Box 4)
  - Baseball, 1967; UA046.001.004.00012 (Box 4)
  - Greater Boston league baseball, 1969; UA046.001.004.00013 (Box 4)
  - Baseball, 1968 -- 1969; UA046.001.004.00014 (Box 4)
  - Baseball, 1970; UA046.001.004.00015 (Box 4)
  - Baseball, 1971; UA046.001.004.00016 (Box 4)
  - Baseball, 1974; UA046.001.004.00017 (Box 4)
  - Baseball, 1975; UA046.001.004.00018 (Box 4)
  - Baseball, 1976; UA046.001.004.00019 (Box 4)
  - GBC baseball, 1976; UA046.001.004.00020 (Box 4)
  - Baseball, 1977; UA046.001.004.00021 (Box 4)
  - [Baseball] [Paul] Bard, 1977 -- 1980; UA046.001.004.00022 (Box 4)
  - Baseball, 1978; UA046.001.004.00023 (Box 4)
  - Baseball, 1979; UA046.001.004.00024 (Box 4)
  - Baseball game file, 1979 -- 1980; UA046.001.004.00025 (Box 4)
  - Baseball, 1980; UA046.001.004.00026 (Box 4)
  - Baseball, 1981; UA046.001.004.00027 (Box 4)
  - Baseball, 1982; UA046.001.004.00028 (Box 4)
  - Baseball, 1983; UA046.001.004.00029 (Box 4)
  - Baseball, 1984; UA046.001.004.00030 (Box 4)
  - Baseball, 1985; UA046.001.004.00031 (Box 4)
  - Baseball, 1986; UA046.001.004.00032 (Box 4)
  - GBL baseball, 1986; UA046.001.004.00033 (Box 4)
  - Baseball, 1987; UA046.001.004.00034 (Box 4)
  - Baseball, 1987 -- 1988; UA046.001.004.00035 (Box 4)
  - Baseball, 1989; UA046.001.004.00036 (Box 4)
  - [Baseball] Field dedication, 1990; UA046.001.004.00037 (Box 4)
  - Basketball records, 1904 -- 1971; UA046.001.004.00038 (Box 4)
    Basketball
  - Basketball til, 1940 -- 1941; UA046.001.004.00039 (Box 4)
  - Basketball, 1946 -- 1947; UA046.001.004.00040 (Box 4)
  - Basketball, 1947 -- 1948; UA046.001.004.00041 (Box 4)
  - Basketball, 1948 -- 1949; UA046.001.004.00042 (Box 4)
  - Basketball, 1949 -- 1950; UA046.001.004.00043 (Box 4)
  - Basketball, 1950 -- 1951; UA046.001.005.00001 (Box 5)
  - Basketball, 1951 -- 1952; UA046.001.005.00002 (Box 5)
  - Basketball, 1952 -- 1953; UA046.001.005.00003 (Box 5)
  - Basketball, 1953 -- 1954; UA046.001.005.00004 (Box 5)
  - Basketball, 1954 -- 1955; UA046.001.005.00005 (Box 5)
  - Basketball, 1955 -- 1956; UA046.001.005.00006 (Box 5)
  - Basketball, 1956 -- 1957; UA046.001.005.00007 (Box 5)
  - Basketball, 1957 -- 1958; UA046.001.005.00008 (Box 5)
  - Basketball, 1960 -- 1961; UA046.001.005.00009 (Box 5)
  - Basketball, 1961 -- 1962; UA046.001.005.00010 (Box 5)
  - Basketball, 1963 -- 1964; UA046.001.005.00011 (Box 5)
  - Basketball, 1964 -- 1965; UA046.001.005.00012 (Box 5)
  - Basketball program, 1965 -- 1966; UA046.001.005.00013 (Box 5)
  - Basketball, 1965 -- 1966; UA046.001.005.00014 (Box 5)
  - Basketball, 1966 -- 1967; UA046.001.005.00015 (Box 5)
  - Frosh basketball, 1966 -- 1967; UA046.001.005.00016 (Box 5)
  - Basketball, 1967 -- 1968; UA046.001.005.00017 (Box 5)
  - Frosh basketball, 1967 -- 1968; UA046.001.005.00018 (Box 5)
  - Basketball, 1968 -- 1969; UA046.001.005.00019 (Box 5)
  - Frosh basketball, 1968 -- 1969; UA046.001.005.00020 (Box 5)
  - Basketball, 1969 -- 1970; UA046.001.005.00021 (Box 5)
  - Basketball, 1970 -- 1971; UA046.001.005.00022 (Box 5)
  - Basketball results, 1971 -- 1972; UA046.001.005.00023 (Box 5)
  - Basketball, 1972 -- 1973; UA046.001.005.00024 (Box 5)
  - Basketball results, 1971 -- 1972; UA046.001.005.00025 (Box 5)
  - Basketball: opponents, 1972 -- 1973; UA046.001.005.00026 (Box 5)
  - Basketball stats, 1973 -- 1974; UA046.001.005.00027 (Box 5)
  - [Basketball] Final hoop stats, 1975; UA046.001.005.00028 (Box 5)
  - Basketball, 1972 -- 1973; UA046.001.005.00029 (Box 5)
  - Basketball, 1973; UA046.001.005.00030 (Box 5)
  - Basketball, 1973 -- 1974; UA046.001.005.00031 (Box 5)
  - [Basketball] ECAC tournament, 1974; UA046.001.005.00032 (Box 5)
  - Basketball statistics, 1973 -- 1974; UA046.001.005.00033 (Box 5)
  - [Basketball] Hoop pictures, 1974 -- 1975; UA046.001.005.00034 (Box 5)
  - Final basketball statistics, opponents, 1974 -- 1975; UA046.001.005.00035 (Box 5)
  - Jackson basketball, 1975; UA046.001.005.00036 (Box 5)
  - [Basketball] MAIAW Tourney, 1975; UA046.001.005.00037 (Box 5)
  - [Basketball] Tufts hoop games, 1975 -- 1976; UA046.001.005.00038 (Box 5)
  - Men's basketball, 1976 -- 1977; UA046.001.005.00039 (Box 5)
  - Men's basketball, 1977 -- 1978; UA046.001.005.00040 (Box 5)
  - Men's basketball, 1978 -- 1979; UA046.001.005.00041 (Box 5)
  - [Basketball] Men's hoop, 1979 -- 1990; UA046.001.006.00001 (Box 6)
  - [Basketball] Men's hoop - Jim Campbell, 1980; UA046.001.006.00002 (Box 6)